Ralph E. Flanders Papers
Ralph E. Flanders Papers
1903-1958
Flanders, Ralph E. (Ralph Edward),1880-1970.
82 linear ft.
Papers of the American engineer, businessman, legislator (U.S. Senator from Vermont, 1946-1959). General correspondence (1923-1940); business correspondence (1930-1934); correspondence on screw threads and gear cutting standardization (1930-1938); correspondence relative to the Vermont Planning Board (1937-1939); senatorial correspondence (1946-1958); personal papers including articles, correspondence, photographs, scrapbooks, speeches, and a genealogy. Correspondents include George D. Aiken, Charles A. Beard, James F. Byrnes, Norman Cousins, Thomas E. Dewey, Dwight D. Eisenhower, Dorothy Canfield Fisher, Alvin H. Hansen, W. Averell Harriman, Herbert Hoover, Harry Hopkins, Harold Ickes, Lyndon B. Johnson, John F. Kennedy, Charles F. Kettering, Henry Cabot Lodge, Joseph McCarthy, Richard M. Nixon, Frances Perkins, Franklin D. Roosevelt, Edward R. Stettinius, Gerard Swope, Myron C. Taylor, Dorothy Thompson, Harry S. Truman, Henry Wallace, and Wendell Willkie.
148981
Biographical History
Ralph E. Flanders was an American engineer, businessman, and legislator. He represented the people of Vermont in the United States Senate for twelve years.
Chronology
1880 Born in Barnet, Vermont
1896 Graduated from high school Central Falls, Rhode Island
1897 Apprenticeship at Brown and Sharpe Manufacturing Company, Providence, Rhode Island
1900 Becomes journeyman machinist and then draftsman
1901-1902 Professional experience in mechanical engineering at Taft-Pierce Manufacturing Company, Woonsocket, Rhode Island and Flather Manufacturing Company
1903 Engineer, International Paper Box Company, Nashua, New Hampshire
1904 Engineer, General Electric Company, Lynn, Massachusetts
1905-1910 Associate editor of Machinery
1910 Sales Engineer, Fellows Gear Shaper Company, Springfield, Vermont
1911 Manager, Fay automatic lathe department of Jones & Lamson Machine Company, Springfield, Vermont
1912 Director, Jones and Lamson Machine Company
1920-1924 Member, National Screw Thread Commission
1924 President, National Machine Tool Builders Association
1932-1936 Director, Social Science Research Council
1933-1946 President, Jones and Lamson Machine Company
1933 Member, Business Advisory and Planning Council
1933 Member, Industrial Advisory Board, National Recovery Administration
1933-1946 President, Bryant Chucking Grinder Company
1934 President, American Society of Mechanical Engineers
1934 Awarded Warner Medal for understanding of economic problems
1938-1941 Director, Shawmut National Bank, Boston, Massachusetts
1938-1946 Director, National Life Insurance Company
1941 Member, Machine Tools Priority Committee, Office of Production Management
1941-1942 President, New England Council
1942-1943 Member, Economic Stabilization Board
1943-1944 Chairman, Machine Tools Committee, War Production Board
1944-1946 President, Federal Reserve Bank of Boston, Massachusetts
1944 Awarded Hoover Medal for Outstanding Public Service
1946 President, American Research and Development Corporation
1946-1958 Member, United States Senate
1958 Private citizen, Springfield, Vermont and Washington, D.C.
Flanders is also the author of several books, among them Gear Cutting Machinery (1909), Spur and Bevel Gearing (1914), Taming our Machines (1931), Platform for America (1936), Toward Full Employment (1938), The American Century (1950), Letter To A Generation (1956), and Senator From Vermont (1961).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Ralph E. Flanders Papers is divided into ten series which fall roughly into three categories: pre-Senatorial, Senatorial, and personal.
The first five series all date from Flanders' pre-Senatorial period. The first, General correspondence (1923-1942, Boxes 1-66), includes both individuals and organizations (American Standards Association, National Screw Thread Commission, Springfield Plumbing and Heating Company, for example) as well as some subject files (e.g. "Invitations") and various trade journals and other publications (e.g., The Architectural Record, Atlantic Monthly). Engineering resource files (Boxes 67-71) contains assorted reference material. Business correspondence (Boxes 72-83) also includes individuals, organizations, trade journals and publications. Records relating to Engineering resources and patent materials (Boxes 84-94) contain patent applications, standards, and more detailed information on particular parts such as turret lathes, hydraulics, pumps, etc. Finally, correspondence related to the State Planning Board of Vermont (Boxes 95-99) includes correspondence, minutes, reports, and other committee-generated material.
Two series are devoted to Flanders' terms in the United States Senate: Senatorial correspondence (Boxes 100-115), which includes correspondence with government bodies and organizations as well as with numerous other senators; and thirteen Voting record notebooks (Boxes 165-170) from the 80th through the 85th Congresses (1947-1958), many of which also contain clippings.
Writings comprises Articles and speeches relating to Flanders' career (Boxes 116-150), books by Flanders (Box 171), broadcasts (Boxes 151-156), and literary and other manuscripts (Boxes 159-164).
Miscellaneous material (Boxes 157, 158, 170, and 171) contains personal items of memorabilia, including scrapbooks, photographs and negatives, clippings and genealogical material.
The 164 boxes of correspondence total approximately 50,000 items. Notable correspondents include Paul Hoffman, Henry Cabot Lodge, Charles A. Beard, Styles Bridges, Norman Thomas, Joseph C. O'Mahoney, Gerard Swope, Myron C. Taylor, Wendell Willkie, Warren R. Austin, George D. Aiken, Samuel Crowther, Dorothy Thompson, Lincoln Filene, Dorothy Canfield Fisher, W. Averell Harriman, Harold L. Ickes, Charles F. Kettering, Charles E. Wilson, Harry Hopkins, Alvin Hansen, Eugene Meyer, Francis Perkins, William Graham Sumner, Dwight David Eisenhower, Herbert Hoover, Harry S. Truman, Richard M. Nixon, Franklin Delano Roosevelt, Lyndon Johnson, John Fitzgerald Kennedy, Henry A. Wallace, Joseph Schumpeter, Winston S. Churchill, John Spargo, Thomas J. Watson, James F. Byrnes, Sidney Hillman, Edward R. Stettinius, Hugh S. Johnson, Richard E. Byrd, Thomas E. Dewey, Mary Roberts Rinehart, Norman Cousins, and others.
Arrangement of the Collection
General correspondence and Business correspondence are each arranged in roughly chronological order; each chronological segment is then arranged roughly alphabetically. As a result, material relating to a particular topic may be located in more than one place (e.g., Champlain Valley Council correspondence is in Box 23 and Box 50). The researcher is advised to review the entire finding aid to ensure locating all relevant material.
The Engineering resource file is arranged in chronological order. Engineering resources and patent information, State planning board files, and Senatorial correspondence are arranged in alphabetical order. Writings are arranged by type and then chronologically within each type.
Subject and Genre Headings
Business and Industry; Politics, government and public administration; Aiken, George D. (George David), 1892-1984.; Beard, Charles A. (Charles Austin), 1874-1948.; Byrnes, James F. (James Francis), 1882-1972.; Cousins, Norman.; Dewey, Thomas E. (Thomas Edmund), 1902-1971.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969.; Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, 1879-1958.; Flanders, Ralph E. (Ralph Edward), 1880-1970.; Hansen, Alvin H. (Alvin Harvey), 1887-1975.; Harriman, W. Averell (William Averell), 1891-1986.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.; Hopkins, Harry L. (Harry Lloyd), 1890-1946.; Ickes, Harold L. (Harold LeClair), 1874-1952.; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.; Kettering, Charles Franklin, 1876-1958.; McCarthy, Joseph, 1908-1957.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994.; Perkins, Frances, 1880-1965.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945.; Stettinius, Edward R., Jr. (Edward Reilly), 1900-1949.; Swope, Gerard, 1872-1957.; Taylor, Myron Charles, 1874-1959.; Thompson, Dorothy, 1893-1961.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; Wallace, Henry A. (Henry Agard), 1888-1965.; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944.; Business Advisory and Planning Council for the Dept. of Commerce (U.S.); National Machine Tool Builders' Association.; New England Council.; Social Science Research Council (U.S.); United States. -- National Recovery Administration.; United States. -- War Production Board.; Legislators -- United States.; Businessmen -- Political activity.; Machine-tool industry -- United States.; Mechanical engineering.; Screw-threads, Standard.; Standards, Engineering.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1901-1953.; United States -- Politics and government -- 1953-1961.; Vermont -- Politics and government.; Clippings (information artifacts); Articles.; Correspondence.; Genealogies (histories); Negatives (photographs); Photographs.; Scripts (documents); Scrapbooks.; Speeches (documents); Businessmen.; Engineers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Ralph E. Flanders, 1963 and his Estate, 1974.
Inventory
- General correspondence files
  - General correspondence, 1923-1927
    - American Machinist (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - American Society of Mechanical Engineers (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - American Society of Mechanical Engineers, Gear Testing Committee (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - American Tool Works (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Benedict, J. G. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Board of Directors of National Machine Tool Builder's Association (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Brown & Sharpe Manufacturing Company (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Chamber of Commerce of the United States of America (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Cincinnati Bickford Tool Company (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Cincinnati Milling Machine Company (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Comparator, Screw Thread (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Daugherty, H. M. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Department of Commerce of the United States (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Dies and Chasers (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Dix, H. P. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - DuBrul, Ernest F. (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Fay Lathe (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Fellows Gear Shaper Company (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Gleason Works (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Gould and Eberhardt (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Heald, James N. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - House of Representatives, United States (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Iles, O. B. (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Industrial Press (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Invitations to Regional Meetings (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Kearney, Edward J. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Kearney and Tricker (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - King Machine Tool Company (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - R. K. LeBlond Machine Tool Company (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Lucas, H. M. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - MacLead, F. N. (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - New Britain McClune Tool Company (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Norton Company (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Pastoral Supply (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Scott, Frank A. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Society of Automotive Engineers, Incorporated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Senate, United States (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Turret Lathe (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - General correspondence
    - Abbott, Geo. H. and Son (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - American Automobile Association (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - American Engineering Council (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - American Society of Mechanical Engineers
      - Davis, C.E. (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Hall, James A. (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Hoover Committee (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - LePage, C. B. (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Rice, Calvin W. (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Stetson, Geo. A. (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Wetter, P. T. (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Wright, Roy V. (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - [Miscellaneous] (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - American Standards Association (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Atlantic Monthly (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Automobile Club of Vermont (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - A, General (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Babbith, Bethel J. (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Batt, William L. (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Beard, Charles A. (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Ba - Be, General (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Bi - Bri, General (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Boy Scouts (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Bro - By, General (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Ca - Cl, General (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Co - Cy, General (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Donham, Wallace B. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - E, General (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Falk Foundation (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Ferguson, Charles W. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Foster, William T. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Freeman, E. L. Company (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - F, General (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Gates, Robert M. (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Ga - Gl, General (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Go - Gy, General (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Ha, General (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - He - Hi, General (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Ho - Hy, General (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - I, General (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - J, General (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - K, General (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - La - Le, General (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Life Extension Institute (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Lombard, Norman (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Longsman, Green and Company (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Li - Ly, General (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Ma - Mc, General (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Mitchell, Wesley C. (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Me - Mi, General (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Mo - My, General (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - National Screw Thread Commission (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - N, General (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - O, General (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Paine, Wilfred A. (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Lough, Pendred (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Pa - Pe, General (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Powell, Coris Worsley (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Pi - Py, General (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Radcliff College (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Ra - Ri, General (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Robinson, Edward (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Rugg, Harold C. (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Ro - Ry, General (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Scribner's (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Sa - Sc, General (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Smith, Elliott Dunlap (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Springfield Plumbing and Heating Company (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Se - Sm, General (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Standard Oil Company (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Sn - Ste, General (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Sti - Sy, General (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Tallmady Hardware C. (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - T, General (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - U, General (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - V, General (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Wallace, L. W. (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Weber, Richard (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Wa - We, General (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Wiggins, E.R. (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Wh - Wy, General (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Y, General (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Z, General (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - General correspondence, 1932-1934
    - Academy of Political Science (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Alber, Louis J. (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Alford, L. P. (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - American Arbitration Association (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - American Committee on Economic Policy (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - American Council (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - American Economic Association (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - American Engineering Council (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - American Forestry Association (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - American Foundation (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - American Manufacturers Export Association (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - American Society of Civil Engineering (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - American Society of Mechanical Engineers
      - [General] (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - Acres, W. P. (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Davies, C.E. (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - LePage, C.B. (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - Stetson, George A. (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - Worthington, C.G. (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - American Standards Association (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - American Standards Association, Agnew, Dr. P.G. (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Armstrong, A.G. (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Arnould, Francis (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Association of Reserve City Bankers (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Association Industries of Massachusetts (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Atkinson, Kerr (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Atwater, William C. (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Austin, Warren R. (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Automobile Club of Vermont (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - A, General (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Babson, Roger W. (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Baldwin, C.F. (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Barker, J.W. (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Barton, Henry A. (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Batt, W.L. (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Bearce, H.W. (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Beneker, Gerrit A. (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Bennett, Edward (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Bettcher, Carl W. (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Billin, Charles E. (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Bliss, Philip E. (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - Blumenthal, Sidney (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - Bogdamov, Peter A. (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - Bogen, Jules I. (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Boor, A. (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Booth, R. H. (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Borsodi, Ralph and Associates (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - Brady, George S. (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - Brentano's (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Britton, Mason S. (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Brookhart, Smith W. (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Buckingham, Earle (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Bullard Company (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Bureau of Standards, United States (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Burleigh, Nathaniel G. (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Business Advisory & Planning Council (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Butler, Hugh (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - B, General (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Carmody, John M. (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Case, George S. (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Case School of Applied Science (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Clement, Charles S. & Company (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Coe, Harry (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Condit, Kenneth H. (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Coyle, David Cushman (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - C, Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Dale, Porter H. (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Davenport, W.S. (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Dickenson, Albert I. (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Donham, Wallace B. (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Druffner, N.H. (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Dunbar, Edith Flanders (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - D, Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Early American Industries Association (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Ehrman, E. H. (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Engineers Club (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Equitable Life Insurance Society (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - Everett, Roberts (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - E, Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Ferguson, Charles W. (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - First National Bank, Springfield, Vermont (Box 11, Folder 32)
    - Frazier, William F. (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - F, Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Gray, William R. (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - G, Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Harris & Ewing (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Harrison, A.D. (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Harrison, Wesley T. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Harwood, E.C. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Hathaway, King (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Hotels (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Hurd, Archibald C. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - H, Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - International Management Institute (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Iron Age (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - I, Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Johnson, Ernest E. (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - J, Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Kennison, Josiah (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Kimball, Dexter S. (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Kimball, J.P. (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - K, Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Ladue, Pomeroy (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Laffin, Harry (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Lawson, R.L. (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Life Extension Institute (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Locke, Mrs. Ione E. (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - London, Harry A. (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Lovell, Proctor (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - L, Miscellaneous (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - M, Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - National Machine Tool Builders' Association (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Nolan, John (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Nonfleet, Helen (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - N, Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Ober, Erik (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Old Corner Book Store (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - O, Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Paine, Wilfred A. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Pearson, May (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Peffer, N.H. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Penniman, A.L. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Penrose, Charles (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - P, Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Raymond, Fairfield E. (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Rutland, Daily Herald (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Q - R, Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Sharpe, Henry D. (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Simpson, C.W. (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Slaney, Harriet E. (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Smart, Howard R. (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Stewart, Warren & Benson (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - S, Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Taylor, Ellery (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Taylor, Mrs. M.E. (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Thorpe, Merle (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Towsen, James W. (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Tuttle, Morton C. (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - T, Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - U, Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Vermont State Chamber of Commerce (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Baron Von Haan, Hugo (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - V, Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Wells, Frank O. (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Westcott, Harry P. (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Wetherill, Lynn (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Wilgus, William J. (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Williams, Percy M. (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Winterrowd, W.H. (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Woolson, William D. (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - W, Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Young, Arthur H. (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - X, Y, Z, Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - General correspondence, 1934-1937
    - Adams, Arthur H. (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Adams, F. B. (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Ames, Adelbert, Jr. (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Affleck, Benjamin Franklin (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Agricultural Committee (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Aiken, George D. (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Albany Society of Engineers (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Alford, L.P. (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Allen, Oliver Field (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Altman, Irving (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - American Academy of Political & Social Science (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - American Association for Advancement of Science (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - American Association of Engineers (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - American Board of Commissioners, July 1935 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - American Engineering Council
      - [General], Jan 1937; Apr 27, 1936;; Jan 1936 (Box 15, Folder 15-17)
      - [General], Jul 1935; Jan 1934,; Nov 1934,; undated (Box 16, Folder 1-4)
      - Stages (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - American Geographical Society (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - American Institute of Bolt, Nut & Rivet Manufacturers (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - American Institute of Consulting Engineers (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - American Institute of Electrical Engineers (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - American Management Association (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - American Mining Congress (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - American National Committee (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - American Program for Social Progress National Industrial Conference Board (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - American Society of Agricultural Engineers, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - American Standards Association (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - American Society of Mechanical Engineers
      - Davis, C. E., 1934-1937 (Box 17, Folder 1-6)
      - Flanders, Ralph E., congratulatory letters on nomination of to presidency (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Hartford, Ernest (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - LePage, C. B. (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Rice, Calvin W. (Box 18, Folder 4)